mypanera.com 2013-06-30

# Privacy Policy :: MyPanera

EFFECTIVE DATE: March 20, 2013

This policy describes the personal information we collect on [www.panerabread.com](http://www.panerabread.com/) and any other authorized sites, services and tools where this policy appears (collectively, this “Site”), how we use it, and when we share it with third parties. Other Program Terms provide additional information about information collected related to that Program(s) and how it is used in connection with the applicable Program.  This policy applies only to personal information collected via this Site, and unless otherwise specifically described herein or in any Program Terms, does not apply to personal information collected offline (including but not limited to information you may provide over the phone, via fax, or when visiting a Panera Bread bakery-cafe or any other website of Panera Bread or on third party sites (see Links to Other Sites section below).  Please note that not all of the features/functionality described are available on or through each portion of the Site. 

By using this Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy and to the Terms of Use statement (“Statement”) governing its use and Program Terms applicable to various Programs. If you have questions, comments or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at <http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact>.  Be sure to check this page periodically for updates, as your continued use of this Site and/or participation in any Program signifies your acceptance of any changed terms. Information Collected and How It Is UsedInformation is collected about you (directly and/or through the activities of franchisees and/or third party suppliers and service providers (“suppliers”)) from various sources, including without limitation the following: (i) information you provide when you contact us though this Site, (ii) information you provide on the account registration pages, surveys, or other submission through this Site and/or in connection with Programs and services available through this Site, (iii) information recorded as a result of your interaction with us and/or franchisees and/or use of the Site (including without limitation historical sales information, information about your location and the device you are using) (through this Site or any other website or in any other manner), (iv) information you provide when you respond to surveys conducted by or on behalf of us and/or franchisees, (v) information we collect about you from outside of this Site, including without limitation information we receive from you in person and/or from third parties (including without limitation from franchisees and referrals from third parties) and (vi) as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy. 

Additionally, information is collected when you participate in certain Programs available on or through this Site.  Please see each applicable Program’s Program Terms for more details about information collected and how it is used. 

The information collected may be combined with other information and may be used and disclosed in a number of ways by us (directly and/or through the activities of franchisees and/or supplier(s)), to help us better understand and serve our customers, including without limitation as described below. 

  * To provide you with, or otherwise respond to your requests for, information and/or services, including but not limited to e-newsletters, access to our webcasts concerning quarterly earnings, marketing programs, identifying a Panera Bread bakery-cafe location and letting you know if you qualify for an Operation Donation program. 
  * To administer Programs and services, including without limitation providing you with services and Program benefits, features and related communications, to verify your participation in the Program or service, to process orders placed and applicable payments, to track submissions, to make your historical ordering information available to you for your future ordering purposes. Note that third party information you provide (for example, your friend in a forward-to-a-friend program) may be maintained in connection with your submission.
  * To provide you with information about new products or services, events in our bakery-cafes, events that Panera or its franchisee’s sponsors, including but not limited to contests, sweepstakes and surveys, and other special offers and marketing programs, which may include information about our affiliated company(ies), franchisees and/or other programs with which any of us or them are involved. 
  * To enhance our customers' and Site users’ experiences in our bakery-cafes, on this Site or in a Program. 
  * To provide Site and Program functionality. 
  * To analyze customer and Site user behaviors and trends. 
  * To conduct research and analysis and to otherwise measure the effectiveness of our online and offline marketing efforts and to develop products, services, and marketing programs. This analysis may include combining personal data drawn from online and offline sources. 
  * To enable and enhance the sales efforts of Panera and/or its franchisees, by phone, email and/or other methods.
  * In connection with certain submissions by you as described in the Statement. 
  * To coordinate Program activities and communications with other marketing programs conducted by us and/or franchisees. 
  * To process your online job application and related information. 
  * To learn more about potential investors in our company, and to allow you to ask questions and receive responses during our webcasts for investors. 
  * As otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use statement and/or Program Terms. 

We do not sell or rent to third parties any of the personal information that you provide to us through this Site, or authorize any of our suppliers to sell or rent any such personal information.  We require that our suppliers agree to maintain the confidentiality of the personal information provided to them.  We do not authorize third parties unaffiliated with Panera Bread to make independent use of your information for their own purposes, such as for direct marketing.  However, aggregated information about users of this Site, customers participating in surveys, registering for e-newsletters or otherwise providing information to Panera (directly and/or through a franchisee and/or supplier) may be combined and utilized by Panera, franchisees and/or suppliers in connection with research, benchmarking and other like uses.   Additionally, we may share your information with our affiliates, franchisees, lenders, investors and/or third party providers. In addition to the uses described above, we share information with these third parties primarily to respond to your specific request or to obtain their service and/or advice on how to improve our business.  Your personal information may be transferred to and within the United States, and certain of your personal information may be transferred to other countries.  Please also see Security of Your Personal Information below.  

Gift Cards We use a third party service provider to make gift card services available to you. The information that you submit while placing a gift card order ("Gift Card Information"), including your name, address, email address, phone number and credit card information, is collected by our third party gift card service provider. Panera Bread does not collect or store your Gift Card Information and will not share this information with other third parties. We require our gift card service provider to maintain the confidentiality of the Gift Card Information that you submit and to use the Gift Card Information only for purposes related to fulfilling and tracking your order, providing you with related customer service and for reporting purposes. Please review the privacy policy on the gift card service site for specific information. We also require our gift card service provider to maintain your Gift Card Information on a secure server and to use at least industry standard encryption technology and security procedures for all payment processing. Please also see the Links to Other Sites section below. 

Franchise Inquiries Information and forms available on the Franchise Information section of this Site are applicable only to prospective franchisees in the United States. If you would like to inquire about becoming a franchisee outside of the United States, please contact our Franchise Development department. 

All information submitted to Panera Bread on our [franchise inquiry form](http://www.panerabread.com/about/franchise/inquiry.php "Complete our franchise inquiry form") is used only to assist in the screening of potential franchisees and will be kept confidential. 

On the franchise inquiry form, we will collect your name, address, email address, other contact information, and certain financial information and qualifications information that you must enter on the form. By submitting this information, you agree that Panera Bread may retain and use the information to respond to your inquiry and to help us improve our franchise marketing efforts. Information on your online form will become part of any application for a Panera Bread franchise that you might later submit. We may disclose your personal information to our business units, agents, affiliates and to other third parties as part of our consideration of any subsequent franchise application. We do not authorize unaffiliated third parties to use your personal information for any purpose other than consideration of your application. Contests/Sweepstakes On occasion, Panera Bread may conduct or sponsor contests/sweepstakes with the opportunity to win prizes. Each contest/sweepstakes has its own terms and conditions ("Official Contest/Sweepstakes Rules"). As part of entering a contest or sweepstakes on-line through this Site or through a third party provider site, certain personally identifiable information (including but not limited to name, address, phone number, etc.) may be required. This information will be used as described in the applicable Official Contest/Sweepstakes Rules.  Surveys From time to time Panera, directly or utilizing the services of third party provider(s), may ask you to participate in surveys. These are voluntary, and you are not required to provide any personal information in connection with participating in a survey. If you do provide personal information, this information will be utilized as described in the privacy policy applicable to the site collecting the information, and any information transferred to Panera shall be utilized as described in Information Collected and How It Is Used. Please note that survey responses received by Panera may not be in an anonymous format and may be associated with any program account number or the like that is associated with you. Job Application InformationIt may be possible to apply for certain jobs at Panera through this Site.  If you choose to apply through this Site, you will be required to provide certain personal information, to complete questionnaires related to evaluation of your qualifications for certain positions, and provide a resume or other similar employment experience description.   You may also be asked to provide your gender and racial/ethnic origin on a voluntary basis, and such information is not provided to anyone involved in the hiring decision.  Panera uses third party suppliers to provide certain of these services.  We encourage you to review their privacy policies. (See Links to Other Sites provisions below). Information you submit online through this Site or through third party supplier sites may be made available to third party suppliers and/or franchisees of Panera, as well as certain employees and contractors of Panera.  You may also fax your résumé to us at 314-909-3320.  Additionally, we may from time to time ask you to apply for certain jobs by email and/or a different fax number.  We protect the confidentiality of such information received by email and fax, however, this online Privacy Policy does not apply to such emails and faxes because they are received offline.

Please note that certain third party suppliers' sites may also allow you to submit your resume and/or otherwise apply for jobs at franchisee locations. Panera Bread is not responsible for the hiring or employment practices of its franchisees. As described in the Our Business Structure section in the Terms of Use applicable to this Site, Panera Bread assumes no responsibility for the privacy practices of our franchisees in their handling of your personal information they collect from you online or offline. If you have questions or concerns about a Panera Bread franchisee, please contact that franchisee directly. If you need assistance reaching a franchisee, please contact us at[ http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact](http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact) or see the For More Information section below.Press Information If you are a member of the press, Panera Bread will collect your name and contact information in order to respond to your [inquiry](http://www.panerabread.com/about/press/inquiry.php "Complete our media inquiry form") submitted on our Press Room web page. We may store your personal information and inquiries for future reference. Scheduling of Events at Panera Bread bakery-cafes  This Site may allow you to schedule certain events in certain Panera Bread bakery-cafes.  Please note that this feature is a test, and only limited number of bakery-cafes in a limited number of markets are participating in this test.  The information you submit with your request to schedule the requested event will be used to send emails confirming the event, if possible, and to create any described supporting materials. Site Usage and Targeted Marketing Information

Like most web sites, this Site gathers traffic patterns, site usage information and other data in order to evaluate our visitors' preferences and the effectiveness of this Site. This usage data does not identify you individually and, except related to any particular Program you choose to participate in, we do not associate it with other personal information (see individual Program Terms for more details on how this information is used). Except as described below or when used in connection with any particular Program, this usage data is used in aggregated form. We may share anonymous, aggregated statistics about visitors to this Site with others outside our Company, and we may allow third-parties to collect and aggregate data through this Site and/or supplier sites accessible from or through this Site.

This Site may use cookies, pixels, web beacons (described below) or other similar technology to enhance the browsing and usage experience on this Site, whether accessed through your computer or a mobile device. The information captured about your activities on this Site will make it possible for us, among other things, (i) to speed navigation and provide you with custom tailored content; (ii) to remember information you gave to us so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit this Site; (iii) to monitor the effectiveness of certain of our marketing campaigns; (iv) to monitor total number of visitors, pages viewed, web address you came from and type of browser you are using, and (v) enforce limitations on downloads described for on-line coupons and other similar offers.

We may from time to time use third party service providers to implement and evaluate our marketing activities and programs, including without limitation activities on our Site and targeted and personalized online advertising on third party websites.  This marketing may be completed using data collected about you over time in connection with Programs you participate in, on this Site and other sites on the Internet and from our other marketing activities and programs.  This data may be collected on an individual basis, based on the use of cookies, pixels, web beacons and other technology, as described below. Some programs may be conducted on an anonymous basis. This information may also be available to and/or shared with the third party service providers and others outside our Company on an anonymous basis for their own business purposes.  For information about opting out of our third party service provider cookies/pixels/web beacons, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative website <http://networkadvertising.org/> and xaxis.com. 

"Cookies" are small files or records that are stored on your computer's hard drive when you visit a website.   To opt out of receiving most cookies related to this Site, including behavioral advertising based upon cookies provided on this Site (including all cookies which are tied to information which would identify you personally (unless you have joined a Program which identifies you personally)), you can clear your browser(s) of all existing cookies, and set your browser(s) to refuse cookies. The “help” functionality of your browser(s) will explain how to do this.  If you refuse cookies, your experience on this Site and using some of our online advertising may be affected — for example you may not be able to utilize all of the functions on this Site.  A “pixel” or “web beacon” is a line of code which is used by a website or third party ad server to cause a cookie to track a user’s activity on particular sites and/or using particular advertising/links, for example, to record that a user has visited a particular webpage and to collect other information about that user on that site, including without limitation the IP address of the computer (and therefore infer information, such as geolocation), web pages being viewed, date/time viewed, and user activity on a particular page.Protecting Our CommunityThe law requires that we and our suppliers may be required to share your personal information and non-personal information pursuant to judicial or governmental subpoenas, warrants or other like orders and in other ways necessary to comply with applicable law. If we are required to do so, we will, of course, obey the law. In addition, notwithstanding any term to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, we and our suppliers reserve the right to use and disclose your personal and non-personal information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or any other similar situation, violations of the Statement, any Program Terms and/or as required by law. Children's PrivacyWe do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. This Site is directed to adults at least eighteen years old.  Certain areas of this Site (for example, [www.MyPanera.com](http://www.mypanera.com/)) are available to persons at least thirteen years old. When a user uses this Site or discloses personal information on this Site, the user is representing to us that he or she is the appropriate age for the portion of this Site, or if he or she is under the referenced age, that he or she is using this Site with the involvement of a parent or guardian.  If a child under thirteen provided this Site with personally identifiable information, we ask that a parent or guardian contact us at <http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact>, and we will promptly delete the child's information from our records.Security of Your Personal Information Panera Bread operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protected systems, and maintains physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to guard the integrity and privacy of these servers and of your personal information. We also require that the suppliers providing services supporting this Site use similar safeguards.  Although we can't guarantee that there will never be a security problem, we and our suppliers that have access to your information take commercially reasonable steps to guard against the loss, misuse or alteration of the personal information we collect on this Site.Transfer of Assets or Business In the event of a transfer or sale of some or all of our business or assets, Panera Bread may disclose your personal information to those involved in such a transfer or sale of business or assets. Changing Your InformationChanging Your Information Moved? Changed email addresses? If you need to update, verify or delete your personal information related to a particular Program or service, please edit your account in the area provided, if available as part of a Program, contact us at <http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact>(please include the name of the program or service in the subject line), or contact us at Customer Resource Group, Panera Bread, 3630 S. Geyer Road St. Louis, MO 63127.  Note that not all fields are able to be changed. If you need to update or verify your personal information related to a job application, or wish to remove yourself from future consideration for other career opportunities, please go to the Careers section of this Site, and use your user name and password to update or verify your personal information or to indicate that you no longer want to receive emails regarding other career opportunities. Please, note, however, that changes made either in an account area or by contacting us directly will not remove your personal information from specific uses for which it was previously provided. This information will be updated as soon as reasonably possible, subject to retention for dispute resolution, troubleshooting and other valid legal or business reasons.  Please note that your historical usage information may remain in our records. Links to Other Sites This Site may provide links to web sites not operated by Panera Bread, including without limitation our supplier(s) related to certain Programs offered through this Site.  Panera Bread requires that its suppliers take steps to keep your personal information confidential.  Notwithstanding the foregoing, Panera Bread assumes no responsibility for third-party websites, including but not limited to, the privacy practices of these third-party sites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave this Site, and we recommend that you review the privacy policies of every web site that collects personally identifiable information from you. This Privacy Policy applies only to this Site. Links to Other Sites This Site may provide links to web sites not operated by Panera Bread, including without limitation our supplier(s) related to certain Programs offered through this Site.  Panera Bread requires that its suppliers take steps to keep your personal information confidential.  Notwithstanding the foregoing, Panera Bread assumes no responsibility for third-party websites, including but not limited to, the privacy practices of these third-party sites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave this Site, and we recommend that you review the privacy policies of every web site that collects personally identifiable information from you. This Privacy Policy applies only to this Site. 

Although this Site may open a new browser window when you click on a link to a third party's site, we do not guarantee that you will receive this alert when you leave this Site. It is your responsibility to determine when you have left this Site. California Privacy RightsBeginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Panera Bread who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at <http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact>  or write us at: Customer Service, Panera Bread, 3630 S. Geyer Road St. Louis, MO 63127. Miscellaneous

  * Capitalized terms referenced in this Privacy Policy but not defined herein shall have the same meaning as identified in the Term and Conditions statement.
  * Headings contained in this Privacy Policy are inserted for convenience of reference only and shall not in any way define or affect the meaning, construction, or scope of any of the provisions contained in this Privacy Policy.
  * Email submissions over the Internet may not be secure. Please consider this fact before emailing any personal or confidential information.

For More InformationFor More Information If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us by contacting us at to <http://www.panerabread.com/about/contact> or writing to us at 3630 S. Geyer Road St. Louis, MO 63127  
© 2009-2013 Panera Bread. All Rights Reserved.  
...
